Privacy
=======

**MiniTool Software Ltd.** is committed to protecting your privacy. We will only collect your personal information for defined purposes. We do not distribute or share your personal information beyond what is strictly necessary to fulfill our obligations to you. We may share your information only with partners who adhere to MiniTool Software Ltd.'s commitment to protecting your privacy. MiniTool Software Ltd. will not sell your personal information in any manner whatsoever.

What information do we collect? What do we use it for?
------------------------------------------------------

When you place an order on our website, your full name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card number will be required. The information is used to complete the transaction and help us provide better support and services to you.

How do the 3rd party credit card processors protect customer's information?
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

MiniTool Software Ltd. uses secure server and other 3rd party credit card processors that encrypt all the customer's personal information before it is sent to us, including name, address, credit card number, etc. Encryption works to prevent any malicious use of your personal information. Your credit card information is only used for online transition.

About third-party AD
--------------------

We may use [third-party advertising companies](http://d1w9iw0aev1fyv.cloudfront.net/pp.html) to serve ads when you visit our website

Information We Collect
----------------------

When you use the Services, we collect the information you give us when using the Services. This includes:

* When you make a purchase, you provide us or the payment processor with payment information, such as your debit or credit card number.
* When you participate in surveys or focus groups, you give us your insights into our products and services.
* If you contact our customer service team, we collect the information you give us during the interaction. Sometimes, we monitor or record these interactions for training purposes and to ensure a high quality of service.

Information we receive from others

We receive information about you from others, including our vendors, our Service Providers and Resellers and our other business partners. We also receive information about you from the third parties that help us operate the Services, such as for fraud detection, digital forensics, and similar functions.

Information collected when you use the Services

When you use the Services, we collect information about which features you use and how you use them and the computer, tablet or mobile telephone ("**Device**") that you use to access the Services (collectively, "**Usage Data**"), which includes:

* **Server Logs**
    
    We collect information about your activity on the Services, such as features you use through our server logs. A server log is a list of the activities that a server performs. MiniTool’ servers automatically collect and store in server logs your search queries, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, time zones, the date and time of your request and referral URL and certain cookies that identify your browser.
    
* **Device information**
    
    We collect information from and about the Device that you use to access the Services, including:
    
    hardware and software information such as Device ID and type, Device-specific settings and characteristics, operating system, identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your Device or browser;

We may link personal data and Usage Data or different types of Usage Data. We also may link publically-available personal data, such as personal data available in public databases. If the linked information may identify an individual person, we treat it as personal data.

Information collected through Data Collection Technology

We use cookies, pixel tags (also known as web beacons, flash cookies, and clear GIFs) and similar technology ("**Data Collection Technology**") to automatically collect information about you when you use the Services. Please read below to learn more about how MiniTool uses Data Collection Technology.

Other information with your consent

We collect other information when you give us permission at the time of collection, such as when you choose to participate in the MiniTool Customer Experience Program (CEP).

Cookies and Other Data Collection Technology
--------------------------------------------

Cookies are small text files that are sent to or accessed from your web browser or your computer's hard drive. A cookie typically contains the name of the domain (internet location) from which the cookie originated, the "lifetime" of the cookie (i.e., when it expires) and a randomly generated unique number or similar identifier. A cookie also may contain information about your computer, such as user settings, browsing history and activities conducted while using the Services. A web beacon (also called a pixel tag or clear GIF) is a piece of computer code that enables us to monitor user activity and website traffic. To learn more about cookies and web beacons, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

How We Use Data Collection Technology: Data Collection Technology helps us improve your experience of the Services by, for example, storing your website language preferences, so you do not have to select it each time you use the Services, compiling statistics about use of the Services, helping us analyze technical and navigational information about the Services, and detecting and preventing fraud.

The Services use the following cookies:

* Strictly necessary cookies, which are required for the operation of the Services. Without them, for example, you would not be able to register or log in for the Services that we may offer.
* Analytical/performance cookies, which allow us to recognize and count the number of visitors, to learn how visitors navigate the Services and to help us to improve the way Services function.
* Functionality cookies, which are used to recognize you when you return to the Services.

We also use Google Analytics which is a Google service that uses Data Collection Technology to collect anonymous information about use of the Services and report website trends.

Your Control of Cookies: Some web browsers (including some mobile web browsers) provide settings that allow you to control or reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your Device. You also may be able to reject Device identifiers by activating the appropriate setting on your Device. Although you are not required to accept cookies or mobile device identifiers, if you block or reject them, you may not have access to all features available through the Services.

Our Statement On Do Not Track Signals: Some web browsers (including Safari, Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Chrome) incorporate a "Do Not Track" ("**DNT**") or similar feature that signals to websites that a user does not want to have his or her online activity and behavior tracked. If a website that responds to a particular DNT signal receives the DNT signal, the browser can block that website from collecting certain personal data about the browser’s user. Not all browsers offer a DNT option, and DNT signals are not yet uniform. For this reason, many website operators, including MiniTool, do not respond to DNT signals.

How We Process Personal Data
----------------------------

MiniTool processes personal data:

* To set up and maintain your account;
* To communicate with you;
* To prevent and investigate fraud and other misuses of the Services;
* To protect our rights and property;
* To operate, manage, secure and improve the Services;
* To respond to your questions and to try to resolve problems with one of our products;
* To complete transactions requested by you;
* To improve the performance and reliability of our products and services using information collected through the MiniTool Customer Experience Program (CEP);
* To help us improve our customer service.

MiniTool processes Usage Data:

* To analyze trends and statistically monitor how many people are using the Services;
* To develop, improve and protect the Services;
* For customer preferences research;
* To audit and analyze the Services;
* To ensure the technical functionality and security of the Services.

To process your information as described above, we rely on the following legal bases:

* Provide our service to you: Most of the time, the reason we process your information is to perform the contract that you have with us to use the Services.
* Legitimate interests: We may use your information when we have legitimate interests to do so. For instance, we analyze users’ behavior on the Services to continuously improve our offerings, marketing our new products and features and process information for administrative, fraud detection and legal purposes.
* Consent: From time to time, we may ask for your consent to use your information for certain specific reasons. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at using the contact information provided at the end of this Privacy Statement.

How We Share Information
------------------------

MiniTool may share personal data collected through the Services as follows:

* Vendors: We share information with our vendors that help us operate the Services, such as by providing customer service, helping us with marketing or testing our security measures. MiniTool will ensure that any vendor with which we share personal data agrees to use commercially reasonable measures to safeguard it.
* Resellers: We share information with our resellers and other third parties that promote, resell and/or white-label the Services.
* Corporate Transaction: We may share and transfer personal data if we are involved in a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control by MiniTool or any affiliated company (in each case, whether in whole or in part).
* When Required by Law: Applicable law may require MiniTool to disclose your personal data if: (i) reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (such as a court order, subpoena or search warrant), government investigation or other legal requirements or (ii) necessary for the prevention or detection of crime (subject in each case to applicable law).
* Other Lawful Disclosures: We also share information if (i) disclosure would mitigate MiniTool’ liability in an actual or threatened lawsuit; (ii) as necessary to protect legal rights of MiniTool, users, customers, vendors, business partners or other interested parties; (iii) to pursue available remedies or limit the damages; (iv) to enforce our agreements; and (v) to respond to an emergency.

MiniTool may aggregate information collected through the Services and remove identifiers so that the information no longer identifies or can be used to directly identify an individual ("**Aggregated Information**"). MiniTool shares Aggregated Information with third parties and does not limit third parties' use of the Aggregated Information.

Your Choices About Your Personal Data
-------------------------------------

* **The right to know what personal data we hold about you:** If you would like to know the personal data that MiniTool maintains about you, please contact us in writing using the contact information below.
* **The right to correct or delete personal data:** The easiest way to correct or delete certain personal data that you have provided to the Services is to contact our support team. If you have additional questions regarding the correction or deletion of the personal data we hold about you, please contact us using the contact information below. Please be reminded that we will review your request but may be restricted in our ability to change or delete your personal data. If the Services are made available to you by a corporate customer that is sponsoring your use of the Services, your eligibility to receive Incentives and Rewards from such parties, if any are offered, may be adversely affected by your election to remove personal data about you from the Services. You must contact the corporate customer directly for further information.  
    We may reject requests for certain reasons, including if the request is unlawful or if it may infringe on trade secrets or intellectual property or privacy rights of a third party.
* **Accountability.** In certain countries, including in the European Union, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how we process your personal data.

Protection & Retention Of Personal Data
---------------------------------------

We take precautions intended to help protect personal data that we collect and store. For example, we protect the information transmitted from your browser to the Services using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software or similar encryption technology. Any transmission is at your own risk. We expect that you will use appropriate security measures to protect your information.

We may suspend your use of all or part of the Services without notice if we suspect or detect any breach of security. If you believe that information you provided to us is no longer secure, please notify us immediately using the contact information provided below.

We keep your personal data only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes and as permitted by applicable law. In practice, this means that we delete or anonymize your account after three (3) years of continuous inactivity unless we must keep it to comply with applicable law; because an issue, claim or dispute has not yet been resolved; or the information must be kept for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud prevention and enhancing users' safety and security. Please note that, although our systems are designed to carry out data deletion processes, we cannot promise that deletion will occur within a specific timeframe due to technical constraints.

### MiniTool Partition Wizard
